<u>AARON YOUNG</u>

Bremerton, WA 916-248-3224 Single Scope Background Investigation Top Secret Eligibility <u>Aaron.c.young@outlook.com</u> www.Mustardmandevelopments.com

Objective

To become an integral part of a team that's goal is to perform magnificent solutions to development for the people. I hope to get a career in development and give the company a motivated, team-focused leader that will inspire the companies' goals and values. I also hope to learn from my experience within a new career by growing as a developer in return bringing my passion for development every day.

Skills

- Java
 - o Android
 - o Application Design Strategies
 - o Google Material Design Guidelines
 - o User Interface and User Experience
 - Object Oriented Design
 - o Eclipse IDE
- Networking
- Communication
- Time Management
- Research
- Database design, data analysis
- Leadership
- Attention to Detail
- Presentations
- Work Experience

- Web Development
 - PHP, HTML, CSS, MySQL, JavaScript
 - o AJAX, Angular. JS
 - o Security Design
 - User Interface
 - o ASP.NET MVC
 - o Git Version Control
- Microsoft Applications
 - Access, Excel, InfoPath, Word, Outlook, PowerPoint
 - SharePoint (Novice-Intermediate)
 - Windows Server 2008 R2
 - Windows Server 2012 R2
 - SQL Server 2012, 2014 (Novice)
 - o Visual Studio 2010, 2013
- Linux experience

Olympic College, Full-Time Student
Bachelors of Applied Science Information Systems
January 2013 to Present

Description:

Presidential Scholar and Deans Scholar GPA: 3.85

Puget Sound Naval Shipyard and Intermediate Maintenance Facility (PSNS & IMF), Bangor Site
Assistant Security Manager
February 2014 – Present

Description:

Responsible for the careful management of Bangor site security operations in the following security disciplines; Information Security, Personnel Security, Anti-Terrorism, Physical Security and Industrial Security. Primary advisor for all matters dealing with information security at the Bangor site and designated lead department security coordinators for the second largest department in the organization of 12,000+ employees.

Anti-Terrorism officer responsible for the implementation of security procedures and risk assessment for the Commanding Officer. Responsible for reporting all policies and regulations to the installation Anti-Terrorism Officer and inform of local strategies for the program.

Awarded two gold level awards for excellence in designing Microsoft InfoPath and Access applications that support the goals PSNS & IMF.

AARON YOUNG 1

PSNS & IMF, BremertonSite Security Assistant March 2013 – February 2014

Description:

Responsible for the safety and security of thousands of controlled items. Provide direction to personnel in the protection of sensitive information, newly implemented or revised security policy, and the protection of proprietary equipment per established directive. Provide physical security protection of people, facilities, information and equipment per Intelligence Community Directive.

United States Marine Corps (USMC) Infantry Team Leader June 2008 –November 2012

Description:

Lead and supervise up to 20 team members and equipment assigned to all Marines by ensuring goals and objectives of the unit are communicated. Train team members and assign responsibilities to meet goals and objectives. Brief and counsel team members and ensure accountability of actions and appropriate disciplinary actions. Accountable for the placement of team members in proper work situations and ensuring standards and requirements are met. The outcome of these actions resulted in a team that had a high standard of excellence and met timelines for every training event and combat scenario as well as getting Marines home safely by performing well in combat. Throughout my entire employment with the Marine Corps, I have been responsible to maintain the weapons/gear assigned to me (list of weapons shown in Certification & Certifications). Perform maintenance on this equipment, which requires disassembly, repair/maintenance and reassembly of this equipment. The amount of which approximating close to a minimum 100,000 dollars to as most as 1,000,000.

Certifications:

- CompTIA Security+ Certification; License Number: JWH8GTSM3GVEYM7E 1/2016
- Defense Security Service, Security Fundamentals Certification 4/2014
- Defense Security Service, Physical Security Certification 4/2014
- Defense Security Service, Security Asset Practitioner Certification 10/2015
- Test Out: Security Pro; Certification ID: CQBQ, Candidate ID: UKD3 8/2014
- Test Out: Network Pro; Certification ID: CXGM, Candidate ID: UKD3 10/2014

Education

- Java I & IIOOP
- Android Development
- Information Systems
 Integration
- Business Statistics
- Information Assurance
- LAN Administration
- Small Group Communication

- Web Development
- Project Management
- Database Design & Analysis
- XML
- Business & Leadership
- Digital Sociology

TRANSCRIPT PROVIDED ON REQUEST

AARON YOUNG 2